<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nina Obiar</title>
    <link>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nina Obiar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a MSc candidate in the Pollock Lab&#xD;. My research passions lie in the intersectionality between biodiversity and ecosystem services. In all aspects of my work I aim to uphold my identity as a Filipino immigrant as I continue to mold my research here in Tiohtià:ke/Montreal. I am grateful to have been brought up navigating the delicate balance between superstition and science, inherited from generations of farmers in my family who imparted wisdom on sensing the health of our livestock and predicting harvest yields.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/cv/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;Previous&#xD;Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&#xD;/ [pdf]&#xD;View the PDF file here.&#xD;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leadership &amp; Community Involvement</title>
      <link>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/outreach/</guid>
      <description>Diversity in Science My passion for celebrating diversity and fostering inclusivity is a driving force in how I approach science. As a student representative of the Inclusion and Diversity Commity within the Canadian Botanical Association&#xD;, I am constantly working to advocate for opportunities and events that nurture an inclusive botanical community.&#xA;Being a female immigrant scientist can have its challenges&amp;hellip; but being able to see positive change our institutions - albeit at a slower pace than one would hope - gives me hope!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/research/</guid>
      <description>Scroll down to learn more about my research interests&#xA;Biodiversity &amp;amp; Ecosystem Services &amp;lsquo;Useful&amp;rsquo; plants (i.e., food, medicine, materials) can be minimizied in biodiversity valuation. I investigate whether we can bridge biodiversity and ecosystem services. More specifically, I delve deeper into whether classic biodiversity metrics can be an effective surrogate for useful plant diversity.&#xA;Climate change effects on Alberta bird rehabilitation In collaboration with the Alberta Institute of Wildlife Conservation, I created a framework to investigate the effects of the climate crisis on Alberta avian population.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Experience</title>
      <link>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Data Analysis Statistics Instruction Recently, I was able to help guide first-year undergraduates delve deeper into the world of statistics as a teaching assistant. I facilitated engaging laboratory sessions, empowering them with statistical analysis techniques and data interpretation skills. Collaborating closely with other instructors, we crafted lab materials and assessments to foster a deeper comprehension of statistical principles, making the subject both accessible and hopefully enjoyable.&#xA;Indigenous Ways of Knowing Research Coach During my undergraduate degree at the University of Calgary, I was lucky enough to be a Course-Based Research Experiences Research Coach at the Taylor Institute of Teaching and Learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
