<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ens on Nina Obiar</title>
    <link>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ens on Nina Obiar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/en/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/en/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a MSc candidate in the Pollock Lab&#xD;. My research passions lie in the intersectionality between biodiversity and ecosystem services. In all aspects of my work I aim to uphold my identity as a Filipino immigrant as I continue to mold my research here in Tiohtià:ke/Montreal. I am grateful to have been brought up navigating the delicate balance between superstition and science, inherited from generations of farmers in my family who imparted wisdom on sensing the health of our livestock and predicting harvest yields.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/en/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/en/cv/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;Previous&#xD;Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&#xD;/ [pdf]&#xD;View the PDF file here.&#xD;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/en/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ninaobiar.github.io/en/en/research/</guid>
      <description>Scroll down to learn more about my research interests&#xA;Biodiversity &amp;amp; Ecosystem Services &amp;lsquo;Useful&amp;rsquo; plants (i.e., food, medicine, materials) can be minimizied in biodiversity valuation. I investigate whether we can bridge biodiversity and ecosystem services. More specifically, I delve deeper into whether classic biodiversity metrics can be an effective surrogate for useful plant diversity.&#xA;Climate change effects on Alberta bird rehabilitation In collaboration with the Alberta Institute of Wildlife Conservation, I created a framework to investigate the effects of the climate crisis on Alberta avian population.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
